praise the
Lord your Excellency the president of
the Republic of
Kenya members ofas barzak who are with
us today in this
place all protocols
observed um good
morning I know today is a busy
day and I take this opportunity
to give thanks to
God for 30
years since
1993 when we sat at zani then I was the
Secretary of Nairobi region which was
only one region
then and we agreed we need to have a
National Church
like any other that is the word then
like any
other and Men Who Sat
agreed and we want to thank God 30 years
down the line I was assistant pastor
then part time in
embassi and we want to thank
God that we are part of this great
celebration
happy 30 years of
age this morning I bring greetings from
my wife they have a mission uh at the
church C
pipeline I agree with the senior
pastor and probably he thought I was
joking uh and I also want to confirm
before the head of the state that I was
not joking who is among the first in
this church I I he asked me S how will
we be serving in this church now that
you are the presiding bishop and I told
him the only day you will see me there
is the day either there's a national
event all you call
me that's what I told him and he thought
I'm not serious and I'm sure now you
approved to my words
because you may be wondering why is it I
don't come
here and I want to make it very clear to
all these
members you have 11 pastors here you
have so many uh leaders
here it will not be prudent for me to
leave the sheep in the penny where I'm
the shepherd to go and attend a sheep in
the penny that as a a shepherd
that will not be
fair it will be a spirit of not being in
the vocation of this
fard and that's why I told
him story actually that's the word I
used that's the word I used to him and I
also want to repeat
again so members of a m
the only thing uh I will slightly just a
simple joke I would slightly make it to
you is that I don't see your
10% for your pastor because I'm your
pastor now you got it right now let's go
to the word of
God let's go to the word of God
um I would like briefly to talk
about the
discipleship because discipleship is
something very
important the theme of this
church is
Colossians which is a very strong
theme which is a very strong
theme a very strong belief and
conviction
in that second
chapter and in that great
first because you want
growth growth rooted in the growth of
Christ Jesus in the scripture but
there's something mentioned there in
Colossians 1 and verse
15 and what is mentioned in that first
is what I want to outline and maybe say
something on where we have read uh our
scripture
today Colossians 2:7 it concludes the
argument that was
raised in chapter 1 and verse
15 which is very
key therefore Believers should continue
to live in
Christ starting now the 31 year you need
to be
reminded of the things that you have
outlined five of them which are very
key that is to
worship meaning to honor God must come
as the first thing in one's
life the second pillar is to be a
faithful
Steward and you remember a faithful
Steward in the old days was the head or
the
chief and in this faithful Steward it
talked of wisdom wisdom must govern
you as you forge ahead the
next years that the Lord will give
you and of course the most important
thing is is the third pillar and that is
where you need to put a lot of your
efforts in missions and
evangelism it is easy for us to do
Mission and evangelism because in the
mission is to strengthen the Believers
with the word of God it is to give them
the
biblical doctrines so that the new
Believers can be encouraged and many of
us in this church and the caliber of the
people of this church I know you can do
that you don't have to be in the front
line for the soldiers to fight and the
general is here and he knows you don't
have to be there but you can make sure
the men in the front line are fully
equipped and our duty in this
congregation is to make sure our men who
are in front line doing the mission work
and
evangelism have the character that is
needed the materials that is
needed and they provide the funds that
is needed for the men who are gifted in
Mission and evangelism can do it better
we we want and this I have to say we
want to make sure that this church in
future God willing there are three
countries that needs
evangelism and that is Bundi and Rwanda
and South Sudan and they're looking at
us they are looking at us together with
Uganda that we move to that direction
and provide the mission and evangelism
of Africa Inland
church not I see Kenya but Africa Inland
church this you can do by making sure
that the things that are needed are
provided for so that people can get the
manuals can get the brur can get small
booklets about the salvation and
grounding the young
Christians the fifth one I have no
problem with it because it is fellowship
and that one you have done
well but I will indeed want now to
mention a a few things on the fourth
point and that's where our scripture was
taken from
discipleship in Luke
9 verse 57 to
62 talks about the
discipleship and this is where I want to
mention a few things to encourage each
and every one of us
so that as we move
forward to the
next 50 years down the line God
willing then we can be very good in so
winning in so winning because the point
is to win the source for Christ and that
is the key point to win the source for
Jesus Christ and to maintain a perfect
church that is equipped
with the knowledge of
God I want to praise our
parents in this church for allowing the
young Church the Sunday
School the children we have seen here to
come one of the reasons we are losing
our children it's that the parents have
shied away from their responsibility
and we must make sure that we allow our
children as highly as possible in the
morning so that they can come hear God's
word be
grounded taught when their mind is not
occupied with many things and they are
able to be people in future to be relied
by the nation to be lied by the church
and to be lied by the n Believers so
please parents allow your children to
come to Sunday school if you don't do it
at that age the moment they above 12
years they don't belong to
you that's the truth so allow them now
as young as they are bring them and the
good thing members of this
church 90% you can
drive 50% you have drivers
and you can allow them to take the
children to Sunday
school you have no any good reason as to
why they cannot because God has provided
you only 10% I would say they will
struggle and those who are 10% that
you're struggling make effort of
bringing them and then at the break of
the service they go to their service and
they attend it that is the only way we
can keep the generation God has blessed
us please do note that thank you thank
you uh senior pastor I I was impressed
honestly speaking when I saw those
children from that place you know you
almost you're almost now a half of AIC
pipeline you are almost there in terms
of in in terms of H Sunday school Sunday
School in AC pipeline is not less than
1200 they actually almost the people
seated here but actually you have done a
good thing I want to thank God for that
that's the only Ministry we can be proud
of because that's our future generation
let's keep them in the word of God in
their
minds Jesus is talking about the cost of
discipleship and the Bible says as he
was walking along the
road one of the men came to
him and said
Lord will I follow you wherever you go I
will follow you wherever you
go but the question of Jesus is so
important he points
that foxes have o
birs of the hair have
Nets but the son of man has nowhere to
lay his
head these are three different
people pictured in this
text and it is indeed the most important
backbone of this church to
disciple people and discipleship has to
do with Mission and
evangelism and Jesus tells this
man
foxes have hes and birds of the hair
have Nets but the son of man has nowhere
to lay his head
amen we have nowhere to lay our head
here on
Earth it is only temporal when our time
has come for us to go
go and the the the picture that Jesus is
giv here in the first man who
desired is that Desiring to follow him
must we must learn to give
up what others consider
Necessities so as to follow
Christ because following Christ
needs a radical
commitment and the Church of Jesus
Christ needs to be
radically
committed in serving
God and that's why he chose this man
foxes birs of their
place but H and the son of man our place
is a Eternal drilling with God and this
is what we need to make sure that we
evangelize
people and I've realized also the best
important people to evangelize are
people of I calling in the
world because you have two things that
people don't
have you have the gift of a particular
position people are under you and
therefore you are qualified to
evangelize through your position without
seeking
permission so you are
gifted you have the
privilege to talk to the people that are
under you because God has placed them in
your hands you cannot shy away from this
because
discipleship has a reward in heaven one
of the crowns out of the six shall be
given so winners so you need to fight
for it so that that day we will be with
Christ you have something to receive
from
him the second
person he said it to another follow
me but he said Lord let me first go and
bu My
Father and Jesus said to him let the
dead bury their own
dead but you go and preach the kingdom
of
God this
man is the most fortunate person in the
scripture out of the 12 disciples that
Jesus Christ
called by
names particulars looking at their
characters this one is the second person
to be called in the same manner as the
disciples were called by Jesus
Christ so he was the most fortunate
person to receive the same calling that
the
disciples received from their master and
their
creator and the point of this
person was so disturbing to Christ he
says let me go and
bu who my
dad we have so many excuses we
make a utopian excuse that you do not
want to serve Christ and that's what
this man
made that is what many of us do we say
oh God give me give me a few years I
arrange and put my house in order I will
serve
you those are the
excuses you can say perhaps if you're a
doctor let me use a doctor or a
policeman people are so busy 24 hours
you can also use that vocation of being
a doctor or a policeman you are so busy
24 hours that you don't have any
time to do the discipleship work and you
use it as an
excuse you say I'm I'm in I'm on
call that's why I can't go to church I'm
on
call but you know that is not the truth
you can also be on call and serve and
disciple the people you serve on daily
bases this man gave a lame excuse to
Christ let me go and bar my father that
is not the truth of the day
people of Palestine of the day they
buried people the same
day the message reached to him your
father is
dead otherwise why is he with Christ if
his father is not
buried I don't know whether you're
getting the joke he saying let me go
he's asking Jesus permission to go and
bury his father which is not true
because the Cure of Palestine you died
you are buried
immediately you remember sap and
anas how quick it was you remember Jesus
Christ how quick it was that's the Cure
of
Palestine but he's giving a lame
excuse and that's why Jesus also uses a
very hard word to
Him Live the dead bury the dead now
that's a very strong word from the
mea what was he
saying he was telling this second
person that proclamation of the Gospel
of the
kingdom of God was
important and that it could not
wait he could not
wait and he saying let the spirit
spiritually
dead bar physically
dead that's what Jesus was telling this
man let the spiritually dead bu what the
physically
dead because he made a lame
excuse he knew very well his father is
dead and buried so what you are asking
to
do is not the truth
and therefore discipleship needs one to
be committed radically committed in this
ministry it's not a m to be at the front
line but you can be one of making the
booklets that people will read for
discipleship and you use that money to
do your
work one of the greatest weakest part of
Africa church is that we do not once we
get saved we do not
invest in having booklets or
models modules for that matter for other
people to
read but we say oh thank you Jesus
salvation belongs to me and me alone and
my God it's important you invest also
your
resources we have kab printing press you
can print any
booklet and you pay so that it is given
people
free and you will have radically
changed the way you
live how many booklets do we print in a
funeral
service in a
wedding in a
ceremony so
many and we don't feel
anything in natur your in fact somebody
says leave that one to me I'll do
it you need to tell the the group of
Pastors in this church that they give
you the the
teachings and then you print it and you
give them and they take it to the Lost
World this one I want to draw attention
to everybody in this country the Church
of Jesus Christ is under siege
and time has
come we do what has to be done to
disciple the people and make sure they
get the
tracks you can go to BHB and sponsor the
pastors here and in actual
fact it is almost
free it is almost free but they ask the
hair time is almost
free how many people listen don't don't
don't lift up your hand but how many
people listen
BHB I know there are so many isn't
it now how many preachers Have you
listened to BHB who are not
AIC with our
staff you can you can be part of that
and you sponsor because that is
discipleship making sure
that you
provide the guidance to the to the new
confes and the people who are not
Believers so proclaiming the
kingdom Gospel of God was important to
the second person in the life of Jesus
Christ but to the third
one he says that is verse 6162
he says and another one also said Lord I
will follow you but let me first go and
Beed them farewell who are at my house
and Jesus said to him
no no
one having put his hand to the plow and
looking back his feet
four my my Bible is New King James
Version the one Reverend Mambo read it
is something
important it said in the last part is
fit for the service of the kingdom of
God but mine is too radical it
says is fit for the kingdom of God
Christians we
must be radicalized in the approach of
preaching the Good News to the lost
world we
must because this is very
important and what does the Bible
say in this third
person is asking The
Authority but Authority had already been
passed to
him he's asking Jesus Jesus is the
authority and he's asking him sir can
you give me
Authority can you give me permission to
go and
bu sorry to go and be farewell to my
family Jesus words
underscored the fact that his message of
the kingdom of God was more important
than anything else even family members
that's what Jesus was saying you know
why once you get
saved by
faith and
believed the finished work work of the
Cross of Calvary of Jesus Christ and you
become a
Believer
immediately you are enthroned with
authority because you are the heir of
the kingdom of God so you don't need
permission again from any other person
to serve in
Christ
service and
therefore many argue
when Elijah was being
called if you read Kings 19 First Kings
19 somewhere
there he
asked when when elishah was being
called by God through
Elijah and he
threw or rather he his clock which he
was
wearing he threw it or
rather he bit this person with it
whatever the case he did with the cloth
but in the Old Testament they would come
and apply the clock on yourself and that
moment Authority has been passed to
you so Elijah when he did this act to
Elijah he passed the authority and
Elijah now became of no consequence
quenes so when he has him
permission that's why Elijah asked him
what have I to do with
you I'm
now finished my
business permission is granted the
moment the clock
touched your
body and that's how it used to happen in
the in the in the Old Testament you
remember even when H when King sa tore
the Garment of priest his his kingdom
ended there you remember Jesus Christ on
the night he was betrayed the high
priest tore His Garment and immediately
he he tore His Garment then the
priesthood of levitical ended and Christ
immediately assumed the priesthood which
is eternal
up to this
moment so what am I saying when you live
the hard life and you are born
again you cannot ask permission to serve
God because Authority is automatically
granted to you by God and The Business
of serving God becomes your
immediate action action plan number one
propagating the Gospel of Jesus Christ
then the other list will
follow and that's why I'm encouraging us
AIC
mman that you take the
lead and preach the good news to the
lost world because you have all the
facilities you have no deficiency in
anything and if you have deficiency in
anything is that you are not saved
because you have
everything you have the
authority you have the power you have
the
knowledge you have the silver and gold
that men look
first so what
else why would you ask permission when
it is granted to you that's what Jesus
is telling this man that's what Elijah
told Elisha I cannot give you I have
nothing to do with you now the authority
is
yours as
imy you have a lot of
authority which you need to
exercise I don't know why you don't
exercise
it and I don't know
why we don't see you on the front line
you know
why in our Constitution and
bylaws this church belongs to
Barak and that's truth number
one and if it belongs to
barasa who else are you asking
permission to go and the
serve so you cannot be like this man
Authority has already been passed to
you this
church has served
I don't want to be political because
every every time you mention a small
thing the Press is writing a different
text this church has served AIC two
presidents in this
country so what other authority are you
asking the president seated in front of
us now is a member of
AIC so what what other authority are you
asking that it cannot not be
provided he has been an elder
here he has served
us and he's serving with us and always
everywhere he goes he
says so you you don't have any
deficiency at all whether literally
spiritually you have 11 pastors unless
you say we add another two
more you have the that is needed in
terms of
service and the worst part of
it I'm I'm now the pastor in
church so for you to use those words of
this
servant you'll not be fair to God
because you have the authority with you
is that right you don't be like now
Elijah Elijah was like
you for Palestine to
plow with a 12 Auction
Company and to
plow your farm with that kind of
Machinery 12
trucks 12
tractors in Palestine that was a very
rich man and the land was so
fertile now
you are very rich This Land Is So
fertile you don't need to ask permission
that's what I'm saying so we want to see
you on the front line want to see you
serving God
faithfully and we want to see you
executing the Mandate of
baraso so
please
discipleship demands total Allegiance
to
Christ so you have that demand from
Christ total
Allegiance because you are serving
Christ and you cannot have a divided
interest like the farmer who looks
back when a farmer is plowing and those
of those who come from lower Eastern and
you plow with a you with a plow you know
when you are plowing moving forward you
don't look back the moment you look back
your hands turn either left or right and
you find that the plow is not in the
line and that's the point Jesus Christ
is arguing
here don't look
back your Lance is to
Christ and do this for him because your
calling
is a high calling it is
irrevocable that is a high calling you
have it is
irrevocable and you need to press
on in this work of the
vineyard may God bless
[Applause]
you as I
conclude
because maybe the next time we get the
permission might be another 5 years and
we'll have
retired to
come um I would like to
pray
one we need to pray and as you have
prayed for so
many many days
one we Africa Inland
Church do not and that is our
our calling we don't like making press
statement and you can't make it unless
given by
bar and we don't like looking like we
take one position or the other but one
of the key things we tell our
congregants is that every decision that
pertains to this country we must be
Seekers of Peace we must seek
peace and we we must pray those are two
things uh we do your Excellency we have
prayed for you you
know but we don't like public
show because not that we are cowards but
we don't want to lose any so and we have
said we all pray we have stood with the
government and we'll keep on doing so
and we'll keep on upholding you if you
ask kirui and the members of barasa that
is our first agenda every time we meet
in barasa
uh that is the first thing we do and I
want us to pray one for this
nation which is very
important so that God will guide and
Lead as long as he guides and
leads Prosperity is
ours and that is what we need more than
anything
else and uh since we will pray two of us
I'll ask now the deputy presiding Bishop
to come and get uh get mik here we want
to do that while I read some texts for
blessings now this is a general blessing
for us all
KY and this might embarrass some of us
but the good thing is is for the best so
can I ask kindly We
Stand now it shall come to pass
if you diligently obey the voice of the
Lord your
God to observe carefully all his
Commandments which I command you
today that the Lord your God will set
you high above all nations of the
earth and all these blessings shall come
upon
you and overtake
you because you obey the voice of the
Lord your
God blessed shall you be in the
city and blessed shall you be in the
country blessed shall be the fruit of
your
body the produce of your
ground and the increase of your
hearts increase of your
kettle and The Offspring of your
flocks blessed shall be your basket and
your KN in
B blessed shall you be when you come
in and the Blessed shall you be when you
go
out the Lord will cause your enemies to
Rise Against
you to be defeated before your face
you shall come out
against they shall come out against you
one
way and flee before you seven
ways the Lord will command the blessings
on you in your
storehouses and in all to which you set
your
hand and he will bless you in the
land which the Lord your God is giving
you the Lord will establish establish
you as a holy people to
himself just as he
saw to
you if you keep the Commandments of the
Lord your God and walk his
ways then all the peoples of the Earth
shall
see that you are called by the name of
the
Lord and they shall be afraid of you
and the Lord will grant you plenty of
goods in the fruit of your
body in the increase of your
livestock and in the produce of your
ground and in the land which the Lord SW
to your fathers to give
you the Lord will
open to you is good
treasure the
Heavens to give the rain in your land in
each
season and to bless you
all the work of your
hands you shall lend to many
nations but you shall borrow To
None the Lord will make you the head and
not the
tail you shall be above
or and not be
beneath if you eat the Commandments of
the Lord your God which I command you
today and be careful to observe
them so you will be not turn asight from
any of The Words which I command you
this
day to the right or
left to go after other gods
to serve
them deput presiding we pray then I will
conclude let's pray our gracious and
Heavenly Father once again this
afternoon we are humble before
you we are so grateful Lord that you be
you have been with
us since the beginning of this meeting
and since the beginning of this
separation you have been faithful to all
of
us since the path of this
church what else can we say
Lord about of saying that you are so
grateful you are a marvelous God and a
loving God and a merciful
god and the Bible says as you are
faithful
God will always serve us will always see
the Deep things in our
hearts to all of us who are standing
before you today this
afternoon you knew us even before the
path and that Lord you have ordered our
steps and that Lord you have good plan
for each and every one of
us and so Lord with your so great F and
thankful and we pray Lord that we
continue to be committed and faithful
unto
you to follow you and to serve you
Faithfully God I want to
pray for this local church and the
entire leadership of this local
church and as I pray for the entire
church Africa Inland church that Lord
Lord you will
bestowed Your Glory and Honor upon
us that you'll Endor your V and Glory
upon each and every one of us so that we
continue to serve you
Faithfully we honor you Lord for his
Excellency the president of the Republic
of
Kenya and the leadership of this
country and now Lord want to pray for
your blessings for him
and the entire leadership the Lord you
will protect them against the power of
the enemy that you will prosper
everything they'll do for the people of
this
country Lord we pray for him and the
family we pray also for all of us that
we will always app and in the law and
your
word Jehovah Our God we speak your
presence upon all of
us that Lord will
continue to work and serve
you with all our strength and all our
minds forgive us Lord where we are
wrong forgive us Lord where we are not
doing
right forgive us Lord where we are not
doing as you want us to do so that we
live as people
of one country One Nation called Kenya
and that we serve this church by going
out without turning
back we have
read that
Lord the Bible is relating us with a
farmer we need not to look back but
rather to fix our eyes on Jesus Christ
the perfector of our faith we love you
God and so Lord this afternoon we humble
before you and ask for your blessings to
accompany each of us as we go back home
for this is our prayer in Jesus name
amen amen and again
Lord we have read your
word and the blessings that accompany
obedience and we claim them now in the
name of Jesus
Christ and I declare this congregation
blessed of you oh
God and I go against every entrance of
the enemy the devil whether externally
or
internally and we destroy every outer of
the enemy the devil we destroy every
Covenant of the evil one to destroy your
people and all the enemies we put them
under the feet of Jesus Christ and
declare this congregation blessed of you
oh
God and our
father the creator of Heaven and Earth
here stands your
servant the president of the Republic of
Kenya you have chosen
him and nothing else because the choice
is
yours father we command blessings on
him that Lord you give him wisdom to
lead this
nation that you give him Zeal to do
things the way God you command him to
lead these
people because they are your people and
this is a great
nation father give him the wisdom now
that as he executes its duties every day
and every
night your spirit will lead
him and your spirit will guide
him we shower him with the blessings and
his family now we pray for his
government we pray for the three arms of
the government of the Republic of
Kenya that sanity will
prevail we pray also for Recovery of the
economy that Lord you prosper this
nation in his
leadership that at the end we will look
back and give glory to your
name and that you will make
him prosper in
leadership prosper in
peace that his heart will be still in
you we want to thank you for making it
possible for him to come today
here and we honor you for that respect
God
and we declare him blessed of
you and now to him who is able to keep
you from
stumbling and to present you
faultless before the presence of his
glory Jesus
Christ with exceedingly
joy to God Our Savior Jesus Christ who
alone is voice be glory and Majesty
Dominion
and
power both now and
forever amen may God bless you God bless
you thank you